Guide to the Robert College records,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Records of the President
  - Subseries III.5: Annual Reports
    - Reports to the trustees from Black, 1946 (Box 28, Folder 49)
    - Annual Report, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Statement concerning the financial needs of the American colleges in Turkey, 1947 (Box 28, Folder 51)
    - Annual Report, 1950-1958 (Box 28, Folder 52 to 59)
    - Ballantine report on the status of American colleges in Turkey, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 60)
    - Annual Report, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 61)
    - Ballantine final report to the board, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 62)
- Series IV: Records of the Vice President, George H. Huntington
  - General Correspondence, 1927-1952 (Box 29, Folder 1 to 8)
  - Huntington passport, 1910 (Box 29, Folder 9)
- Series V: Records of the Dean
  - Subseries V.1: Edgar Fisher (Restricted)
    - Correspondence Gates/Fisher, 1924 (Box 29, Folder 10 to 11)
    - Correspondence to Fisher from Gates, 1928 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence Albert Staub/Fisher, 1927-1929 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence to Fisher from Huntington, 1928-1932 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - General correspondence, 1930-1932 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence Staub/Fisher/Helen Deering, 1920 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence Fisher/Staub/Deering/Moore, 1931-1933 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence Fisher/Monroe/college officials, 1933-1934 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence re Fisher, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence re Fisher (written in Turkish), 1933 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - "History Outline," circular letter, copies of clippings, 1932-1933 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Addresses on Near East political situation given by Fisher, 1933 (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Subseries V.2: Laurence S. Moore
    - General correspondence, 1927-1935 (Box 29, Folder 23 to 25)
  - Subseries V.3: Harold Scott
    - Correspondence to Black from Scott, 1923-1936, 1941-1942 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence to Scott from Black, 1929-1942 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence to Black from Scott, 1945-1955 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence to Scott from Black, 1948-1955 (Box 30, Folder 4 to 5)
    - "A Trip to Beirut" (account of Scott's trip to inauguration of Stephen Penrose as President of the American University of Beirut), 1948 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence to Scott from Huntington, 1922-1933 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence to Huntington from Scott, 1929, 1933-1940 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence to Scott from Huntington, 1935-1948 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence to Huntington from Scott, 1941-1948, 1951 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - General correspondence, 1922-1936 (Box 30, Folder 11 to 22)
    - Lecture notes (probably prepared at Columbia University), [1925] (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - General correspondence, 1937-1957 (Box 31, Folder 24 to 38)
    - Memorial eulogy; miscellaneous correspondence, 1947-1958 (Box 31, Folder 39)
  - Subseries V.4: Harold Hazen
    - Correspondence to Ballantine from Hazen, 1955-1967 (Box 31, Folder 40)
    - Correspondence to Hazen from Ballantine, 1955-1959 (Box 31, Folder 41)
    - Correspondence re Acting President position for Hazen, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 42)
    - Correspondence to Hazen from Marjorie Hyde Bond, 1961 (Box 31, Folder 43)
- Series VI: Records of the Faculty
  - List of "American Teachers at Robert College", 1863-1850 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence to Reverend Ino Paine, Jr. from Hamlin re teaching position, 1867 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Contracts of employment, 1867, 1877 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence to Wilcox from Robert, 1867-1868 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence to Paine from North, 1869 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Agreement between Robert and Lansing Porter (tutor), 1878 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - General correspondence to Van Millingen, 1878-1879 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - List of examinations, 1880 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Prospectus of RC, tabular view of classes, chart of studies at RC, 1870s-1882 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - "A Report of the Special Committee on the Question of Discipline", 1909 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Adjustment of schedules, 1929 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence to Alfred Zimmern re studies at The Geneva School of International Studies, 1929-1936 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Faculty, miscellaneous, 1930 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Religious Life Committee, prayer meetings, 1930-1931 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Reports of Scholarship and Discipline Committees, 1931-1935 (Box 32, Folder 15)
  - Military Studies, 1936-1939 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - RC Handbook, "Information and Suggestions for Instructors in Robert College", [undated] (Box 32, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence to Laurens Seelye from Black, 1945 (Box 32, Folder 18)
  - List of former American teachers, 1953 (Box 32, Folder 19)
  - Memorial service for Frank Hewitt, 1957 (Box 32, Folder 20)
  - Memorial resolution for Lewis V. Thomas, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 21)
- Series VII: Records of the Students
  - Programme of the Annual Examinations, 1877 (Box 32, Folder 22)
  - Programmes of Class Exhibitions, 1877-1879 (Box 32, Folder 23)
  - Catalogue of students, lists by name, nationality, and age, 1882 1884- 1886, 1889 (Box 32, Folder 24 to 26)
  - Notice of fee increase, 1908 (Box 32, Folder 27)
  - "Rules and Regulations for the Students of RC", 1914 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Notes on "Dr. Eddy's" address, 1920 (Box 32, Folder 29)
  - Commencement Exercise Programs of Robert Academy, 1920-1931 (Box 32, Folder 30)
  - Programs of special events, 1924-1928 (Box 32, Folder 31)
  - Essays written for Peace Day Essay Contest, 1927-1929 (Box 32, Folder 32)
  - Commencement Exercise Programs, 1920s-1940s (Box 32, Folder 33)
  - "Suggestions to Students on Manners" (Robert Academy), 1935 (Box 32, Folder 34)
  - Athletics, John J. Karakash, 1935 (Box 32, Folder 35)
- Series VIII: Records of the Alumni
  - Bulgarians prominent in government circles (with 1800s dates of graduation from RC), 1880s (Box 32, Folder 36)
  - List of graduates by nationality, 1863-1930 (Box 32, Folder 37)
  - Alumni Register of Robert College, 1912-1913 (Box 32, Folder 38)
  - List of graduates by nationality and year, 1921 (Box 32, Folder 39)
  - Alumni Register of Robert College, 1931 (Box 32, Folder 40)
  - "Some Distinguished Graduates of RC and Some Prominent Alumnae of ACG", 1950 (Box 32, Folder 41)
- Series IX: Office of the Trustees, New York
  - Correspondence Huntington/Staub, 1923-1933 (Box 33, Folder 1 to 8)
  - Correspondence Scott/W.A. Robinson, assistant treasurer, 1938-1942 (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 10 to 11)
  - Correspondence to Black from Staub, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1924 (Box 33, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1926 (Box 34, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Staub/Henry Schauff1er, acting president, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, 1927 (Box 34, Folder 21 to 22)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1927-1928 (Box 34, Folder 23 to 25)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, 1928-1929 (Box 34, Folder 26 to 29)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1929-1930 (Box 35, Folder 30 to 32)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Gates, Moore, 1930-1931 (Box 35, Folder 33 to 35)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Staub, 1931 (Box 35, Folder 36 to 37)
  - Correspondence Monroe/Staub, 1932 (Box 35, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Monroe, Gates, Lynn Scipio, and Huntington, 1932-1933 (Box 35, Folder 39 to 40)
  - Correspondence to Monroe from Staub, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 41 to 42)
  - Correspondence Staub/Monroe, 1933 (Box 35, Folder 43)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Monroe, 1934 (Box 35, Folder 44)
  - Correspondence to Monroe from Staub, 1934 (Box 36, Folder 45)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Monroe, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 46)
  - Correspondence to Monroe from Staub, 1935 (Box 36, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence Staub/Wright, 1935-1936 (Box 36, Folder 48 to 52)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 53 to 54)
  - Correspondence to Wright from Staub, 1937 (Box 36, Folder 55)
  - Correspondence Staub/Wright, 1937-1938 (Box 36, Folder 56 to 57)
  - Correspondence to Wright from Staub, 1938 (Box 37, Folder 58 to 59)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1938-1939 (Box 37, Folder 60 to 61)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright and Scott, acting president, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence to Wright from Staub, 1939 (Box 37, Folder 63 to 64)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1940 (Box 37, Folder 65 to 66)
  - Correspondence to Wright from Staub, 1940-1941 (Box 37, Folder 67 to 68)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1941 (Box 37, Folder 69)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright and Scott, 1941 (Box 37, Folder 70)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright and Scott, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 71 to 71)
  - Correspondence to Wright and Scott from Staub, 1942 (Box 38, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright in Washington, D.C., as Coordinator of Information, 1941-1942 (Box 38, Folder 74)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 74 to 76)
  - Correspondence to Wright and Scott from Staub, 1943 (Box 38, Folder 77)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Scott, acting president, 1943-1944 (Box 38, Folder 78 to 79)
  - Correspondence to Scott from Staub, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 80)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Wright, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 81 to 82)
  - Correspondence to Wright from Staub, 1944 (Box 38, Folder 83)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Black, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 84)
  - Correspondence to Black from Staub, 1944 (Box 39, Folder 85)
  - Correspondence Black/Staub, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 86)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Black, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 87 to 88)
  - Report of Dr. James L. Barton's visit to the State Department, 1923 (Box 39, Folder 89)
  - Correspondence Staub/Coffin, 1929-1954 (Box 39, Folder 90 to 94)
  - Correspondence Staub/Huntington, 1930 (Box 39, Folder 95)
  - Correspondence Staub/Huntington, 1935;1938 (Box 39, Folder 96 to 97)
  - Correspondence to Black from Staub, 1945 (Box 39, Folder 98)
  - Correspondence to Staub and Harry R. Snyder from Black, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 99)
  - Correspondence to Staub and Snyder from Black, 1946 (Box 39, Folder 100 to 101)
  - Correspondence to Black from Staub and staff, 1947 (Box 39, Folder 102 to 103)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Black, 1947-1948 (Box 39, Folder 104 to 107)
  - Fisher and William Patton (director of NECA) to Black, 1948 (Box 39, Folder 108 to 109)
  - Proposed Point IV Request for ACG submitted by Robert Hardy, 1951 (Box 39, Folder 110)
  - Duncan Ballantine, biography and terms of appointment, 1954-1961 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Ballantine file, terms of appointment, benefits and resignation, 1955- 1961 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - "Assessment of Operational Needs," memo prepared by Ballantine, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Ballantine, 10-year plan, 1958-1961 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Ballantine, speeches and articles, 1959 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Ballantine/Fred Grinnell, assistant to chairman of the Board of Trustees, 1958 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, Ballantine, 1958-1960 (Box 40, Folder 7 to 10)
  - Ballantine, report re student demonstrations, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence re appointment of Cornelius Bull, 1959-1960 (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence re candidates for assistant to the president, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Press release re appointment of Harold Hazen, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 14)
  - Hazen, correspondence, news release, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence Hazen, 1961-1962 (Box 40, Folder 16)
  - Patrick Malin, biography and terms of appointment, 1961-1962 (Box 40, Folder 17 to 18)
  - Correspondence re appointment of Malin, 1961 (Box 40, Folder 19)
  - Malin, financial memo to the trustees, 1962-1964 (Box 40, Folder 20)
  - Malin, general correspondence to NY Office, 1962-1964 (Box 40, Folder 21 to 23)
  - Correspondence and memos re appointment of Orhan Mersinli as Turkish vice president of RC, 1962-1953 (Box 40, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with Margaret Bloomer, secretary to President Malin, 1962-1965 (Box 41, Folder 25 to 26)
  - Correspondence with Mrs. Caroline Malin, 1961-1965 (Box 41, Folder 27 to 28)
  - Correspondence with Howard Hall, vice president, 1961-1964 (Box 41, Folder 29 to 33)
  - Ford Foundation: Hazen, report on RC Engineering School, 1955 (Box 41, Folder 34)
  - Ford Foundation: Ballantine, "Summary of Development Program for ACG and RC", 1956 (Box 41, Folder 35)
  - Ford Foundation: Carter Davison, report on RC and ACG, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 36)
  - Ford Foundation: Ballantine memo re RC Development Program, 1957 (Box 41, Folder 37)
  - "Secondary Education in Turkey, Observation, Problems, and Recommendations," by John J. Rufi, 1952 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Report on ACG by Rosemary Park, 1955 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Proposals to the Ford Foundation, 1956 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - A Fund Raising Report and Recommendations by Kersting, Brown & Company Inc., 1957 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - A Report to the Ford Foundation by Carter Davidson and Paul A. Dodd, 1957 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - A Proposal to the Olin Foundation re A Graduate Engineering Building at RC, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Teaching English at RC and ACG by Jane Carey, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Proposed development of the RC School of Business, Administration and Economics; other reports, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Report on the American Hospital of Istanbul by Dr. Rolf Lium, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Interim Report on Second Century Fund Activities by Goldthwaite Dorr and Jane Page, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 10)
  - Re consolidation of RC and ACG by Alfred Odgen, 1959 (Box 42, Folder 11)
  - "The Role of RC in Turkey's Economic Life" by Peter G. Franck, 1960 (Box 42, Folder 12)
  - Report of the Turkish National Commission on Education, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 13)
  - RC Research Center, Proposed Constitution, 1961 (Box 42, Folder 14)
  - Management Survey by Cresap, McCormick and Paget, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 15)
  - Report to U.S. Department of State on RC and ACG by Carl M. Franklin, 1963 (Box 42, Folder 16)
  - Peace Corps Contracting Manual, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 17)
  - Peace Corps Training Program, 1963 (Box 43, Folder 18 to 19)
  - Correspondence, statements, memoranda re U.S. government funds, 1956-1958 (Box 43, Folder 20 to 21)
  - Correspondence, statements, memoranda re U.S. government funds, 1959 (Box 43, Folder 22)
  - U.S. Government, Atomic Energy Commission, guide to grants, 1958- 1959 (Box 43, Folder 23)
  - Correspondence Air Force-Aircraft Nuclear Propulsion Department re surplus laboratory equipment, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence with U.S government agencies (A.I.D.) re grants, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 25)
  - General correspondence, A.I.D., 1962-1963 (Box 43, Folder 26)
  - U.S. Government reports, Washington, D.C., visits, 1960-1963 (Box 43, Folder 27)
  - Correspondence with government agencies re grants, 1961-1964 (Box 43, Folder 28)
  - U.S. Government surplus properties, 1963-1964 (Box 43, Folder 29)
  - Summary, U.S. Government grants to RC and ACG, 1964 (Box 43, Folder 30)
  - A.I.D., personnel biographical data, 1962 (Box 43, Folder 31)
  - U.S. Government, Senate Foreign Relations Committee, statement on, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence with the Subcommittee for the Department of State and Justice and the Judiciary, 1960 (Box 43, Folder 33)
  - U.S. Government, Mutual Security Act, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 34)
  - U.S. Government, reports on Ankara visit, 1961-1962 (Box 44, Folder 35)
  - U.S. Government, President's Directive on U.S. Balance of Payments, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 36)
  - U.S. Government grants, Department of the Navy, Office of Naval Research (Box 44, Folder 37)
  - Bond re Washington aid, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 38)
  - U.S. Government, "Profiles," correspondence, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 39)
  - U.S. Government, "Profiles," worksheets, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 40)
  - A.I.D.: summary presentation, 1962 (Box 44, Folder 41)
  - Summary, U.S. Government grants to RC and ACG, 1962-1963 (Box 44, Folder 42)
  - Summary, U.S. Government grants to RC and ACG, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 43)
  - U.S. Government grants, Reallocation of funds, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 44)
  - Congressional Hearing Information, 1963 (Box 44, Folder 45)
- Series X: Financial Records
  - Financial statements and invoices, 1860s-1890s (Box 45, Folder 1 to 4)
  - Financial, miscellaneous, [undated] (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Washburn bank book, 1869-1876 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Financial statements prepared by Washburn, treasurer, 1871-1872 (Box 45, Folder 7 to 8)
  - Edward Ede to Washburn, itemized account, 1874-1877 (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Financial statements and correspondence re Washburn, 1886-1889 (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Financial statements of the president and trustees, 1897-1898 (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Securities held by the trustees, 1899 (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Financial documents, miscellaneous, 1800s (Box 45, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Construction of buildings, financial statements, 1904-1907 (Box 45, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Correspondence to Gates from A.D.Hamlin re construction of buildings, 1910 (Box 45, Folder 17)
  - Finance Committee Minutes, 1932-1942 (Box 46, Folder 18 to 20)
  - Correspondence pertaining to Beneficiary Funds, 1880-1933 (Box 46, Folder 21 to 23)
  - Correspondence to Wright re investments, sale of property (includes letters from Schieffelin), 1939-1942 (Box 46, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence from Wright to Trustees re financial situation of the college, 1939-1943 (Box 46, Folder 25)
  - Correspondence re buildings and Minimum Profits Tax, 1931-1936 (Box 46, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence re the Minimum Profits Tax, 1935-1944 (Box 46, Folder 27 to 28)
  - War claims and shipments during World War I, 1914-1921 (Box 46, Folder 29)
  - Report on construction at RC for 1913-1914 and Report of the Boarding Department, 1914 (Box 46, Folder 30)
  - Report of the Boarding Department Memo re gifts tax, 1930 (Box 46, Folder 31)
  - Treasurer's Reports, Samuel Anderson, 1913-1914 (Box 47, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence Washburn/Anderson, 1913-1914 (Box 47, Folder 33)
  - Correspondence to Anderson from A.T. Schauffler, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 34)
  - Correspondence to Schauffler from Anderson, 1915 (Box 47, Folder 35)
  - Correspondence to Anderson from Staub, 1919 (Box 47, Folder 36)
  - Correspondence to Anderson from Gates, 1920 (Box 47, Folder 37)
  - Correspondence to Gates from Anderson, 1920 (Box 47, Folder 38)
  - Correspondence to Anderson from Staub, 1920-1921 (Box 47, Folder 39)
  - Budget from Finance Committee, 1920 (Box 47, Folder 40)
  - Correspondence Anderson/Cleveland Dodge, 1914-1919 (Box 47, Folder 41 to 43)
  - Dodge, financial statements, 1917-1919 (Box 47, Folder 44)
  - Annual Reports of the Bursar, 1918-1941 (Box 47, Folder 45 to 46)
  - Correspondence to Staub from Herman Kreider, 1943 (Box 47, Folder 47)
  - Correspondence Black/Kreider, 1946-1948 (Box 47, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence from Kreider to the NY Office, 1942-1948 (Box 47, Folder 49 to 51)
- Series XI: Official College Events
  - "Laying of the Cornerstone of Robert College", 1869 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Annual Examinations, 1868-1970s (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Founder's Day Address, "How Robert College Came Founded," by Van Millingen, 1909 (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Founder's Day Address, "Commemorative Exercises: Centennial of the Birth of Cyrus Hamlin," by Gates, 1911 (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Founder's Day Address by Gates, 1918-1926 (Box 48, Folder 5 to 7)
  - Founder's Day Address, "In Memory of Cleveland Dodge," by Gates, 1927 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Founder's Day Address by Gates, 1929-1932 (Box 48, Folder 9 to 11)
  - Founder's Day Address, "Tribute to Dr. H.H. Barnum, 1937 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Founder's Day, letter from Gates, 1946 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - RC Commencement Addresses, 1943, 1948, 1952 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Dedication of Henrietta Washburn Hall, 1914 (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - RC Vacation Musicales and Services, 1917 (Box 48, Folder 16 to 17)
  - Fundraising: Reports and Brochure:s
    - "Statements in Regard to Robert College" 1873 (Box 48)
    - "Shall Robert College be Sustained," "Why Should I Interest Myself in RC", [1878] (Box 48, Folder 20)
    - Letter addressed to faculty on financial needs of RC (George Washburn), 1880s (Box 48, Folder 21)
    - "The Origin and History of Robert College", 1881 (Box 48, Folder 22)
    - "Robert College of Constantinople: 1863-1890" (Box 48, Folder 23)
    - "Robert College, Constantinople, Turkey" (Box 48, Folder 24)
    - "Robert College, its Work and its Needs" (Box 48, Folder 25)
    - "Address of Rev. Gates to the Trustees" (Box 48, Folder 26)
    - "The Story of Robert College at Constantinople" (Box 48, Folder 27)
    - "Robert College at the End of the War" (Box 48, Folder 28)
    - "What Robert College Needs" (Box 48, Folder 29)
- Series XII: Publications
  - The Robert College Record, 1919-1923 (Box 49, Folder 1 to 2)
  - The Robert College Herald, 1930-1933 (Box 49, Folder 3 to 5)
  - Istanbul American Colleges, Alumni Bulletin, 1953-1955, 1957-1962, 1964-1968 (Box 49, Folder 6 to 9)
  - The Alumni Bulletin continues as Robert College: Alumni Magazine, 1968 to 1978 (Box 49)
  - Constantinople College News, 1916 to 1920. Descriptive articles about ACG during wartime years (Box 49)
  - Constantinople College News Notes, 1924 to 1928. (Box 49)
  - Robert College of Istanbul and the American College for Girls News, 1960 to 1970. Published to "promote understanding of the work of the American Colleges in Istanbul." (Box 49)
  - This Box also contains runs of magazines published jointly by members of the Near East College Association. Included are the News Letter, 1922 to 1926 and the Near East Colleges News Letter, 1927 to 1939. Articles contain specific news about the colleges and general information about educational trends in the Near East. (Box 49)
  - The Bosphorus, 1961 to 1963. (Box 49)
  - Campus News, 1957. (Box 49)
  - Constantinople College News, 1916-1920 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Constantinople College News Notes, 1924-1926, 1928 (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - "Trustees of Robert College and the Syrian Protestant College," Joint Office, Bulletin No.1, 1920 (Box 50, Folder 12)
  - News Letter, Robert College of Istanbul and Syrian Protestant College at Beirut (AUB), 1920-1926 (Box 50, Folder 13 to 14)
  - Near East Colleges Newsletter, 1917-1932, 1934-1939 (Box 50, Folder 15 to 16)
  - Near East Service Quarterly (January, April), 1940 (Box 50, Folder 17)
  - "Near East Service" pamphlet, 1942-1943 (Box 50, Folder 18)
  - Campus News, 1957 (Box 50, Folder 19)
  - RC and ACG News (Alumni Association Bulletins), 1950-1970 (Box 50, Folder 20 to 22)
  - The Bosphorus (Robert Academy), 1961-1963 (Box 50, Folder 23)
  - Robert College Alumni Magazine, 1968, 1970, 1972-1978 (Box 50, Folder 24 to 25)
- Series XIII: Historical Writings
  - The Levant Times and Shipping Gazette, 1870 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Translation of articles from "Phare du Bosphore", ca. 1873 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Articles on Americans in Turkey, 1873 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Review of Edward Dicey's book on Bulgaria, with reference to Washburn, 1894 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper articles on Turkey, 1890s (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Article on Robet College in The Outlook,1905 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Washburn's article on the revolt of 1908 (Box 51, Folder 7)